Finding Aid for the Edwin Bower Hesser Papers LSC.1071
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Prints, ca. 1920-1945; 6 boxes, 19 oversize boxes
  - A. Large Hessercolor, ca.1932-1943
    - Brunette Model A (2 of 10), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 42, Folder 6)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model A posing on a chair in a fuzzy yellow jacket and a blue button-down shirt.
    - Brunette Model A (3 of 10), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 42, Folder 7)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model A posing with flowers and semi-nude covered in a rainbow-colored sheet.
    - Brunette Model A (4 of 10), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 42, Folder 8)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model A posing semi-nude, covered in a rainbow fabric
    - Brunette Model A (5 of 10), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 42, Folder 9)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model A posing semi-nude, covered in a rainbow fabric.
    - Brunette Model A (6 of 10), ca. 1932-1943; 4 items. (Box 43, Folder 1)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model A in various hats.
    - Brunette Model A (7 of 10), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 43, Folder 2)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model A semi-nude.
    - Brunette Model A (8 of 10), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 43, Folder 3)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model A in pink, silk outfit. Includes 16 x 12" pint of the same shot.
    - Brunette Model A (9 of 10), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 43, Folder 4)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model A posing with an ornate scarf and semi-nude, in a transparent yellow sheet.
    - Brunette Model A (10 of 10), ca. 1932-1943; 8 items. (Box 43, Folder 5)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model A posing semi-nude in a black and red transparent cape while holding flowers. Includes shots of her posing with a pink embroidered top with flowers.
    - Brunette Model B (1 of 2), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 43, Folder 6)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model B posing in a tulle outfit with flowers.
    - Brunette Model B (2 of 2), ca. 1932-1943; 10 items. (Box 43, Folder 7)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model B posing in different hats, casual attire, and formal attire.
    - Brunette Model C (1 of 6), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 44, Folder 1)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model C posing in a red silk dress, in a white dress with a hat, and in a snow scene with snowballs.
    - Brunette Model C (2 of 6), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 44, Folder 2)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model C posing semi-nude with an embroidered pink sheet.
    - Brunette Model C (3 of 6), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 44, Folder 3)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model C posing with embroidered pink sheet wrapped around her with a flower in her hair. Includes cut-out photo.
    - Brunette Model C (4 of 6), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 44, Folder 4)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model C posing with an umbrella in a studio, in Hawaiian attire with a lei, and in formal attire. Includes exterior shots in casual attire.
    - Brunette Model C (5 of 6), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 44, Folder 5)
      10 x 13" exterior shots of unidentified Brunette Model C posing in a bathing suit with umbrella.
    - Brunette Model C (6 of 6), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Brunette Model D, ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 44, Folder 7)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified brunette model posing in a ruffled blue and white formal dress.
    - Brunette Model E (1 of 2), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 45, Folder 1)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model E in casual and formal attire.
    - Brunette Model E (2 of 2), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Brunette models (1 of 5), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 45, Folder 3)
      10 x 13" shots of various unidentified brunette models in formal and casual attire.
    - Brunette models (2 of 5), ca. 1932-1943; 7 items. (Box 45, Folder 4)
      10 x 13" shots of various unidentified brunette models in Asian attire, and bathing suits.
    - Brunette models (3 of 5), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Brunette models (4 of 5), ca. 1932-1943; 8 items. (Box 45, Folder 6)
      10 x 13" and 8 x 10" shots of various unidentified brunette models in formal and casual attire.
    - Brunette models (5 of 5), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 45, Folder 7)
      10 x 13" shots of various unidentified various brunette models in casual attire.
    - Food and color tests, ca. 1932-1943; 7 items. (Box 46, Folder 1)
      10 x 13" shots of food on display and color tests.
    - Hesser, Eve (1 of 6), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 46, Folder 2)
      5 10 x 13" shots of Eve Hesser modeling Asian attire.
    - Hesser, Eve (2 of 6), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 46, Folder 3)
      10 x 13" shots of Eve Hesser in formal attire and with puppy.
    - Hesser, Eve (3 of 6), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 46, Folder 4)
      10 x 13" shots of Eve Hesser modeling with flowers and Hawaiian lei, in casual attire with hat, and in flower print dress with hat.
    - Hesser, Eve (4 of 6), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 46, Folder 5)
      10 x 13" shots of Eve Hesser posing with flowers.
    - Hesser, Eve (5 of 6), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 46, Folder 6)
      10 x 13" shots of Eve Hesser modeling festive, costumed, and ethnic attire with flowers.
    - Hesser, Eve (6 of 6), ca. 1932-1943; 3 items. (Box 46, Folder 7)
      10 x 13" shots of Eve Hesser modeling 17th century attire with a powdered wig. Also includes shots of her wearing a Spanish style hat.
    - Lithographs based on Hessercolor, ca. 1932-1943; 14 items. (Box 46, Folder 8)
      11 x 12.5" lithograph portraits of women based on Hessercolor.
    - Men portraits (1 of 4), ca. 1932-1943; 7 items. (Box 47, Folder 1)
      10 x 13" portraits of unidentified men.
    - Men portraits (2 of 4), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Men portraits (3 of 4), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Men portraits (4 of 4), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 47, Folder 4)
      10 x 13" portraits of unidentified men in uniform and costumes for a production.
    - Outdoor scenes (1 of 3), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 47, Folder 5)
      10 x 13" shots of a number of outdoor scenes. Includes a shot of UCLA's Royce Hall.
    - Outdoor scenes (2 of 3), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 47, Folder 6)
      10 x 13" shots of outdoor scenes.
    - Outdoor scenes (3 of 3), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Red-haired model, ca. 1932-1943; 4 items. (Box 47, Folder 8)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified red-haired model in winter attire with Christmas wreath.
    - Theatrical and film scenes (1 of 2), ca. 1932-1943; 4 items. (Box 47, Folder 9)
      10 x 13" and 8 x 10" shots of actors in various unidentified theatrical and film productions.
    - Theatrical and film scenes (2 of 2), ca. 1932-1943; 4 items. (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Women portraits, ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 48, Folder 1)
      10 x 13" portraits of unidentified women.
    - Women--festive, international, ruffled, and costume attire modeling, ca. 1932-1943; 2 items. (Box 48, Folder 2)
      10 x 13", 8 x 10", and 1 mounted 8 x 10" shots of models in festive, costumed, and international attire. The mounted print is signed by Hesser.
    - Women--hats, veils, and headwear modeling (1 of 4), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 48, Folder 3)
      10 x 13" shots of various models in hats.
    - Women--hats, veils, and headwear modeling (2 of 4), ca. 1932-1943; 7 items. (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Women--hats, veils, and headwear modeling (3 of 4), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Women--hats, veils, and headwear modeling (4 of 4), ca. 1932-1943; 4 items. (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Women--props modeling (1 of 2), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 48, Folder 7)
      10 x 13" shots of models posing with cigarettes.
    - Women--props modeling (2 of 2), ca. 1932-1943; 3 items. (Box 48, Folder 8)
      10 x 13" and 8 x 10" shots of models posing with flowers.
    - Women--semi-nude, nude, and erotic attire modeling, ca. 1932-1943; 3 items. (Box 48, Folder 9)
      10 X 13" shots of various unidentified women modeling nude in a studio or outside.
  - B. Large black and white, ca. 1920-1945
    This subseries consists of large format black and white prints featuring portraits of models and persons photographed by Edwin Bower Hesser. The photographs feature women, men, and children in casual, semi-formal, and formal attire; nude, semi-nude and nude women; women in costume and festive attire; various animals; women in winter clothes; men in military uniforms; couples; models with various props; various exterior scenes; theatrical and film scenes; and women dancing. There are two boxes of mounted photographs signed by Hesser. Files are arranged alphabetically according to subject.
    - Advertisements, ca. 1930-1945; 5 items. (Box 24, Folder 1)
      11 x 14" and 13 x 16" black and white shots of various advertisement style set-ups.
    - Animals, ca. 1935-1945; 7 items. (Box 24, Folder 2)
      11 x 14" black and white portraits of dogs and cats.
    - Children (1 of 4), ca. 1935-1945; 13 items. (Box 24, Folder 3)
      11 x 14" black and white portraits and head shots of unidentified young boys and girls.
    - Children (2 of 4), ca. 1935-1945; 14 items. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Children (3 of 4), ca. 1935-1945; 6 items. (Box 24, Folder 5)
      13 x 16" black and white portraits and head shots of unidentified young boys and girls.
    - Couples, ca. 1930-1945; 20 items. (Box 24, Folder 6)
      11 x 14" and 13 x 16" black and white portraits shots of various couples.
    - Documentation and tests, ca. 1930-1945; 8 items. (Box 24, Folder 7)
      11 x 14" black and white prints of documents and tests.
    - Hesser, Eve (1 of 3), ca. 1930-1940; 15 items. (Box 24, Folder 8)
      11 x 14" black and white portraits and head shots of Hesser modeling various outfits.
    - Hesser, Eve (2 of 3), ca. 1930-1940; 16 items. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Hesser, Eve (3 of 3), ca. 1930-1940; 12 items. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Men--casual attire, ca. 1943-1945; 18 items. (Box 25, Folder 3)
      11 x 14" and 13 x 16" black and white portraits of men in casual attire.
    - Men--costume and festive attire, ca. 1940-1945; 5 items. (Box 25, Folder 4)
      11 x 14" black and white portraits of men in costumes and festive attire.
    - Men--formal attire (1 of 3), ca. 1940-1945; 22 items. (Box 25, Folder 5)
      11 x 14" black and white portraits and head shots of unidentified men in formal attire (coat and tie).
    - Men--formal attire (2 of 3), ca. 1940-1945; 19 items. (Box 25, Folder 6)
      11 x 14" and 13 x 16" black and white portraits and head shots of unidentified men in formal attire (coat and tie).
    - Men--military uniforms, ca. 1935-1945; 13 items. (Box 25, Folder 7)
      11 x 14" black and white and color portraits and head shots of unidentified men in military uniforms.
    - Men--smoking (1 of 2), ca. 1940-1945; 12 items. (Box 25, Folder 8)
      11 x 14" black and white portraits of men in various attire smoking cigarettes and pipes.
    - Men--smoking (2 of 2), ca. 1940-1945; 5 items. (Box 25, Folder 9)
      11 x 14" and 13 x 16" black and white portraits of men in various attire smoking cigarettes and pipes.
    - Outdoor scenes and buildings, ca. 1935-1945; 9 items. (Box 26, Folder 1)
      11 x 14" black and white prints of trees, nature scenes, beaches, buildings, and architecture.
    - Outdoor scenes and trees, ca. 1930-1945; 10 items. (Box 26, Folder 2)
      11 x 14" and 13 x 16" black and white shots of various outdoor scenes and trees.
    - Theatrical and film productions, ca. 1930-1945; 17 items. (Box 26, Folder 3)
      11 x 14" black and white prints of various stills from unidentified theatrical and film productions.
    - Women--bed, couch, and chair scenes modeling (1 of 7), ca. 1925-1945; 13 items. (Box 26, Folder 4)
      11 x 14" black and white portraits and head shots of unidentified women posing while laying on a bed, couch, or chair.
    - Women--bed, couch, and chair scenes modeling (2 of 7), ca. 1925-1945; 13 items. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Women--bed, couch, and chair scenes modeling (3 of 7), ca. 1925-1945; 10 items. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Women--bed, couch, and chair scenes modeling (4 of 7), ca. 1925-1945; 13 items. (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Women--bed, couch, and chair scenes modeling (5 of 7), ca. 1925-1945; 15 items. (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Women--bed, couch, and chair scenes modeling (6 of 7), ca. 1925-1945; 12 items. (Box 26, Folder 9)
      11 x 14" and 13x 16" black and white portraits and head shots of unidentified women posing while laying on a bed, couch, or chair.
    - Women--casual attire (1 of 6), ca. 1925-1945; 25 items. (Box 27, Folder 1)
      11 x 14" black and white portraits and head shots of unidentified women in casual attire, such as sweaters, blouses, and dresses.
    - Women--casual attire (2 of 6), ca. 1925-1945; 18 items. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Women--casual attire (3 of 6), ca. 1925-1945; 18 items. (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Women--casual attire (4 of 6), ca. 1925-1945; 19 items. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Women--casual attire (5 of 6), ca. 1925-1945; 14 items. (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Women--casual attire (6 of 6), ca. 1925-1945; 17 items. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Women--close-ups (1 of 4), ca. 1925-1945; 21 item. (Box 27, Folder 7)
      11 x 14" black and white close-up portraits of women in various poses.
    - Women--close-ups (2 of 4), ca. 1925-1945; 13 items. (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Women--close-ups (3 of 4), ca. 1925-1945; 9 items. (Box 27, Folder 9)
      13 x 16" black and white close-up portraits of women in various poses.
    - Women--dance modeling, ca. 1925-1935; 15 items. (Box 28, Folder 1)
      11 x 14" black and white action shots of unidentified women dancing.
    - Women--exterior modeling (1 of 2), ca. 1935-1945; 12 items. (Box 28, Folder 2)
      11 x 14" black and white portrait shots of women modeling outdoors. Framed in medium and long shots.
    - Women--festive, international, ruffled, and costume attire modeling (1 of 8), ca. 1925-1945; 13 items. (Box 28, Folder 3)
      11 x 14" black and white portraits and head shots of women modeling ruffled, low cut, and strapless attire. Includes shots of women in Latin-inspired dress and women in various costumes.
    - Women--festive, international, ruffled, and costume attire modeling (2 of 8), ca. 1925-1945; 9 items. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Women--festive, international, ruffled, and costume attire modeling (3 of 8), ca. 1925-1945; 15 items. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Women--festive, international, ruffled, and costume attire modeling (4 of 8), ca. 1925-1945; 15 items. (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Women--festive, international, ruffled, and costume attire modeling (5 of 8), ca. 1925-1945; 14 items. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Women--festive, international, ruffled, and costume attire modeling (6 of 8), ca. 1925-1945; 14 items. (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Women--festive, international, ruffled, and costume attire modeling (7 of 8), ca. 1925-1945; 8 items. (Box 28, Folder 9)
      13 x 16" black and white portraits and head shots of women modeling ruffled, low cut, and strapless attire. Includes shots of women in Latin-inspired dress and women in various costumes.
    - Women--formal attire (1 of 3), ca. 1925-1945; 16 items. (Box 29, Folder 1)
      11 x 14" black and white portraits and head shots of women in formal attire, such as furs and gowns.
    - Women--formal attire (2 of 3), ca. 1925-1945; 14 items. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Women--formal attire (3 of 3), ca. 1925-1945; 3 items. (Box 29, Folder 3)
      13 x 16" black and white portraits and head shots of women in formal attire, such as gowns.
    - Women--hats, veils, and headwear modeling (1 of 3), ca. 1925-1945; 18 items. (Box 29, Folder 4)
      11 x 14" black and white portraits and head shots of women modeling hats, veils, or other types of headwear. Includes a hand colored print.
    - Women--hats, veils, and headwear modeling (2 of 3), ca. 1925-1945; 16 items. (Box 29, Folder 5)
      11 x 14" black and white portraits and head shots of women modeling hats, veils, or other types of headwear.
    - Women--hats, veils, and headwear modeling (3 of 3), ca. 1925-1945; 17 items. (Box 29, Folder 6)
      11 x 14" and 13 x 16" black and white portraits and head shots of women modeling hats, veils, or other types of headwear.
    - Women--interior modeling, ca. 1940-1945; 14 items. (Box 29, Folder 7)
      11 x 14" and 13 x 16" black and white portrait shots of women modeling various clothes indoors. All shots framed in medium and long or long shots.
    - Women--props modeling (1 of 4), ca. 1925-1945; 9 items. (Box 29, Folder 8)
      11 x 14" black and white portrait shots of women modeling with various props. Includes shots of women modeling with flowers, fruit, house ware, and art props.
    - Women--props modeling (2 of 4), ca. 1925-1945; 11 item. (Box 29, Folder 9)
      11 x 14" black and white portrait shots of women modeling with various props. Includes shots of women modeling with flowers, fruit, pottery, brushes, and fabric.
    - Women--props modeling (3 of 4), ca. 1925-1945; 16 items. (Box 30, Folder 1)
      11 x 14" and 13 x 16" black and white portrait shots of women modeling with various props. Includes shots of women modeling with flowers, fruit, shoes, brushes, and fabric.
    - Women--props modeling (4 of 4), ca. 1925-1945; 12 items. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Women--semi-formal and business attire (1 of 4), ca. 1925-1945; 18 items. (Box 30, Folder 3)
      11 x 14" black and white portraits and head shots of women in semi-formal and business attire, such as blouses, dresses, and suits.
    - Women--semi-formal and business attire (2 of 4), ca. 1925-1945; 11 item. (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Women--semi-formal and business attire (3 of 4), ca. 1925-1945; 11 item. (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Women--semi-formal and business attire (4 of 4), ca. 1925-1945; 5 items. (Box 30, Folder 6)
      13 x 16" black and white portraits and head shots of women in semi-formal and business attire, such as blouses, dresses, and suits.
    - Women--semi-nude, nude, erotic attire modeling (1 of 3), ca. 1920-1945; 12 items. (Box 30, Folder 7)
      11 x 14" black and white portrait shots of women modeling semi-nude, nude, and in lingerie, erotic, and revealing attire.
    - Women--semi-nude, nude, erotic attire modeling (2 of 3), ca. 1920-1945; 15 items. (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Women--semi-nude, nude, erotic attire modeling (3 of 3), ca. 1920-1945; 4 items. (Box 30, Folder 9)
      13 x 16" black and white portrait shots of women modeling semi-nude, nude, and in lingerie, erotic, and revealing attire.
    - Women--winter attire modeling, ca. 1935-1945; 3 items. (Box 31, Folder 1)
      11 x 14" black and white portrait shots of women modeling winter attire.
    - Women--wrapped in mesh or fabric (1 of 8), ca. 1920-1940; 19 items. (Box 31, Folder 2)
      11 x 14" black and white portrait shots of naked or semi-nude women wrapped in mesh or fabric.
    - Women--wrapped in mesh or fabric (2 of 8), ca. 1920-1940; 12 items. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Women--wrapped in mesh or fabric (3 of 8), ca. 1920-1940; 15 items. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Women--wrapped in mesh or fabric (4 of 8), ca. 1920-1940; 14 items. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Women--wrapped in mesh or fabric (5 of 8), ca. 1920-1940; 15 items. (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Women--wrapped in mesh or fabric (6 of 8), ca. 1920-1940; 14 items. (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Women--wrapped in mesh or fabric (7 of 8), ca. 1920-1940; 15 items. (Box 31, Folder 8)
      13 x 16" black and white portrait shots of naked or semi-nude women wrapped in mesh or fabric.
    - Children (4 of 4), ca. 1935-1945; 2 items. (Box 32, Folder 1)
      16 x 20" black and white portraits and head shots of unidentified young boys and girls.
    - Men--formal attire (3 of 3), ca. 1940-1945; 1 item. (Box 32, Folder 2)
      16 x 20" black and white portraits and head shots of unidentified men in formal attire (coat and tie).
    - Women--bed, couch, and chair scenes modeling (7 of 7), ca. 1925-1945; 4 items. (Box 32, Folder 3)
      16 x 20" black and white portraits and head shots of unidentified women posing while laying on a bed, couch, or chair.
    - Women--casual attire, mounted, ca. 1925-1935; 1 item. (Box 32, Folder 4)
      14 x 17" color portrait of woman in casual attire. Portrait is black and white, but colored with color pencil.
    - Women--casual attire, mounted, ca. 1925-1935; 1 item. (Box 32, Folder 5)
      16 x 20" color portrait of woman wrapped in casual attire with scarf around neck. Portrait is black and white, but painted over with various colors.
    - Women--close-ups (4 of 4), ca. 1925-1945; 5 items. (Box 32, Folder 6)
      16 x 20" black and white close-up portraits of women in various poses.
    - Women--exterior modeling (2 of 2), ca. 1935-1945; 3 items. (Box 32, Folder 7)
      16 x 20" black and white portrait shots of a women modeling imposed on paper with shot of building imposed on paper.
    - Women--festive, international, ruffled, and costume attire modeling (8 of 8), ca. 1925-1945; 10 items. (Box 32, Folder 8)
      16 x 20" black and white portraits and head shots of women modeling ruffled, low cut, and strapless attire. Includes shots of women in Latin-inspired dress and women in various costumes.
    - Women--wrapped in mesh or fabric (8 of 8), ca. 1920-1940; 3 items. (Box 32, Folder 9)
      16 x 20" black and white portrait shots of naked or semi-nude women wrapped in mesh or fabric.
    - Women--semi-nude, nude, erotic attire modeling, mounted, ca. 1925-1935; 1 item. (Box 32, Folder 10)
      16 x 20" color portrait of woman semi-nude. Portrait is black and white, but painted over with various colors.
    - Women--wrapped in mesh or fabric, mounted, ca. 1925-1935; 1 item. (Box 32, Folder 11)
      14 x 17" color portrait of woman wrapped in spider-web shawl. Portrait is black and white, but colored with color pencil.
    - Women--wrapped in mesh or fabric, mounted, ca. 1925-1935; 1 item. (Box 32, Folder 12)
      16 x 20" color portrait of woman wrapped in multi-colored fabric with furry edge. Portrait is black and white, but painted over with various colors.
    - Mounted Photographs (1of 2), ca. 1920-1945; 18 items. (Box 36, Folder 1)
      11 x 14" and 16 x 20" black and white and Hessercolor mounted prints of various portraits of men and women. Some mounted prints have Hesser's autograph.
    - Mounted Photographs (2 of 2), ca. 1920-1945; 29 items. (Box 49, Folder 1)
      11 x 14" black and white mounted prints of various portraits of women. Some mounted prints have Hesser's autograph.
    - Dove, Billie (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Pickford, Mary (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Woman and child (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Woman--headshot (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Man--headshot (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - C. Small black and white, ca. 1925-1945
    This subseries consists of small format black and white prints featuring portraits of models and persons photographed by Edwin Bower Hesser. The photographs feature women, men, and children in casual, semi-formal, and formal attire; nude, semi-nude, and erotic modeling women; women in costume and festive attire; various animals; women in bathing suits; women in winter clothes; men in military uniforms; couples; models with various props; various exterior scenes; theatrical and film scenes; and women dancing. Files are arranged alphabetically according to subject.
    - Animals, ca. 1935-1945; 18 items. (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Various sizes of black and white photographs of various animals such as dogs, cats, and deer.